<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Accounting</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Accounting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 20:53:16 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>intangibles goodwill fapi0001aapaapae</title>
      <link>/2017/04/24/intangibles-goodwill-fapi0001aapaapae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 20:53:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/24/intangibles-goodwill-fapi0001aapaapae/</guid>
      <description>Remember: Goodwill = Purchase Price - Fair value of identifiable net assets (of seller)
Goodwill is an intangible asset with indefinite live that can be impaired.
Question: Anheuser-Busch InBev reached an agreement in 2016 to buy SABMiller for a purchase price of $106 billion for SABMiller, making for the biggest beer acquisition on record and one of the largest in corporate history. The fair value of the net identifiable assets of SABMiller before the acquisition was $93 billion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ending inventory fai0002aap</title>
      <link>/2017/04/24/ending-inventory-fai0002aap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 20:11:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/24/ending-inventory-fai0002aap/</guid>
      <description>Remember: Beginning inventory + Purchases - Cost of Goods Sold = Ending inventory
Beginning inventory of 2015 = Ending inventory of 2014
Question: The ending inventory for the year ended December 31, 2014, is understated. How will this erros affect the net income for 2014 and 2015?
2014 overstated; 2015 understated
2014 overstated; 2015 no effect
2014 overstated; 2015 no effect
2014 understated; 2015 overstated
Solution: Point 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>depreciation gain cash fafs0001es</title>
      <link>/2017/04/24/depreciation-gain-cash-fafs0001es/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 19:26:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/24/depreciation-gain-cash-fafs0001es/</guid>
      <description>Remember: Cash from the sale of property, plant and equipment is equal to the value of the asset (net of amortization or depreciation) plus/minus the gain/loss.
In the indirect method the expenses (e.g., depreciation expense) or gains that do not involve cash are added to the net profit to find the cash from operating activities.
Question: During 2015 Castro Company buys patents for $10,310 (paid in cash) and a building for $91,950 (paid in cash).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>net realizable value situations fai0001ae</title>
      <link>/2017/04/24/net-realizable-value-situations-fai0001ae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 19:02:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/24/net-realizable-value-situations-fai0001ae/</guid>
      <description>Remember: The Net Realizable Value (NRV) of the inventory is the value for which the inventory can be sold. If the inventory cannot be sold for an amount higher than its cost (i.e., the NRV is lower than the cost of inventory) then the inventory should be reported at the NRV amount instead of its cost.
Question: Which of the points below describes a situation where the Net Realizable Value is higher than the cost of inventory?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>