<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Accounting</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Accounting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 18:51:58 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>equity versus consolidation method fain0006ee</title>
      <link>/2017/06/09/equity-versus-consolidation-method-fain0006ee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 18:51:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/09/equity-versus-consolidation-method-fain0006ee/</guid>
      <description>Remember:
Under the equity method the investment account is affected by the proportional changes in the investee’s net assets (net assets is that same as assets minus liabilities so net assets is another name for equity).
The consolidation method requires the following steps:
Eliminate the investment account of the parent and eliminate the total equity of the subsidiary
Add the assets of the parent with the assets of the subsidiary</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>investment balance fain0005aap</title>
      <link>/2017/06/09/investment-balance-fain0005aap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 18:42:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/09/investment-balance-fain0005aap/</guid>
      <description>Remember:
Under the equity method the investment account is affected by the proportional changes in the investee’s net assets (net assets is that same as assets minus liabilities so net assets is another name for equity).
Question: Forecast Financials B.V. pays €420,000 to buy 40% of the ordinary shares of a Index Finance B.V. During the accounting period Index Finance B.V. Reports an net income of €50,000, declares and pays a cash dividend of €15,000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>equity method fain0004ar</title>
      <link>/2017/06/09/equity-method-fain0004ar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 16:24:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/09/equity-method-fain0004ar/</guid>
      <description>Remember:
Under the equity method the investment account is affected by the proportional changes in the investee’s net assets (net assets is that same as assets minus liabilities so net assets is another name for equity).
Question:
Which of the following statements is correct:
Under the equity method, the proportional share of profit from associates (accounted for under the equity method) is subtracted from the profit of the investor
Under the equity method, the proportional share of dividends from associates (accounted for under the equity method) increases the profit of the investor</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fair value and equity method fain0003ean</title>
      <link>/2017/06/09/fair-value-and-equity-method-fain0003ean/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 16:08:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/09/fair-value-and-equity-method-fain0003ean/</guid>
      <description>Remember: A company that invests in the shares of other companies (i.e., an investor) can use three accounting methods to record these investments: (1) fair value method (for Treasury Shares [e.g., treasury shares can be short-term investments in other companies, usually in small percentages] and Available-for-Sales securities [e.g., available-for-sales securities can be long-term investments in other companies, usually in small percentages]); (2) equity method (for investments in associates [e.g., when the investor has between 25% and 50% of the shares of the investee]); (3) consolidation method (for subsidiaries [e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>trading securities fain0002aap</title>
      <link>/2017/06/09/trading-securities-fain0002aap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/09/trading-securities-fain0002aap/</guid>
      <description>Remember: A company that invests in the shares of other companies (i.e., an investor) can use three accounting methods to record these investments: (1) fair value method (for Treasury Shares [e.g., treasury shares can be short-term investments in other companies, usually in small percentages] and Available-for-Sales securities [e.g., available-for-sales securities can be long-term investments in other companies, usually in small percentages]); (2) equity method (for investments in associates [e.g., when the investor has between 25% and 50% of the shares of the investee]); (3) consolidation method (for subsidiaries [e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>available for sales fair value fain0001ar</title>
      <link>/2017/06/09/available-for-sales-fair-value-fain0001ar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 12:48:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/09/available-for-sales-fair-value-fain0001ar/</guid>
      <description>Remember: A company that invests in the shares of other companies (i.e., an investor) can use three accounting methods to record these investments: (1) fair value method (for Treasury Shares [e.g., treasury shares can be short-term investments in other companies, usually in small percentages] and Available-for-Sales securities [e.g., available-for-sales securities can be long-term investments in other companies, usually in small percentages]); (2) equity method (for investments in associates [e.g., when the investor has between 25% and 50% of the shares of the investee]); (3) consolidation method (for subsidiaries [e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inventory from financial statements fai0006au</title>
      <link>/2017/04/25/inventory-from-financial-statements-fai0006au/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 12:24:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/25/inventory-from-financial-statements-fai0006au/</guid>
      <description>Remember: Beginning Balance + Increases – Decreases = Ending Balance
Question From the financial statements of Philips it is known that a write-down of inventories to net realizable value amounted to EUR 10 million for the year ended December 31, 2016. Based only on the information avaliable, it is reasonable to conclude that:
The cost of inventory Philips purchased exceeded the cost of inventory sold during the year ended December 31, 2016</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>use cash flows statement fafs0004au</title>
      <link>/2017/04/25/use-cash-flows-statement-fafs0004au/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 11:26:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/25/use-cash-flows-statement-fafs0004au/</guid>
      <description>Remember: The cash flow statement, the investing activities section, is used to see the cash paid for purchases of property, plant and equipment.
The depreciation, amortization and impairment expense can be usually seen in the cash flow statement, the operating activities section. The depreciation expense decreases the profit.
Question Based on the financial statements of AstraZeneca Plc, what is the cash amount paid to purchase Property, Plant and Equipment in 2016 and what is the effect of the depreciation, amortization and impairment expense on the operating income in 2016?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>calculate net income fafs0003br</title>
      <link>/2017/04/25/calculate-net-income-fafs0003br/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 11:14:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/25/calculate-net-income-fafs0003br/</guid>
      <description>Remember: Beginning balance equity + Net income - Dividends +/- changes in other comprehensive income = Ending balance equity
Question: A transportation company balance sheet shows at December 31, 2016 and December 31, 2015 the following (in € million):
Account20162015Total assets244226Total liabilities7640During the year ended December 31, 2016, the company paid dividends of €118 million.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inventory gross profit margin fai0005bap</title>
      <link>/2017/04/25/inventory-gross-profit-margin-fai0005bap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 10:50:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/25/inventory-gross-profit-margin-fai0005bap/</guid>
      <description>Remember: Beginning balance + Increases - Decreases = Ending balance
Gross margin = (Sales - Cost of goods sold) / Sales
For Company Glamour it is known that the beginning inventory in January 2016 is $105,968, the net purchases of inventory during January 2016 are $671,708, the net sales revenue during January 2016 is $471,664 and the gross profit rate for January 2016 is 30 percent.
Question:
What is the company’s estimated cost of goods sold for the month of January?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inventory cost flow cash nrv fai0004bapaan</title>
      <link>/2017/04/25/inventory-cost-flow-cash-nrv-fai0004bapaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 10:15:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/25/inventory-cost-flow-cash-nrv-fai0004bapaan/</guid>
      <description>Remember: The cost flow assumptions used to find the cost of goods sold and the ending inventory have no connection with the cash received or paid.
The Net Realizable Value (NRV) of inventory is the value for which the inventory can be sold. If the inventory cannot be sold for an amount higher than its cost (i.e., the NRV is lower than the cost of inventory) then the inventory should be reported at the NRV amount instead of its cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inventory ppe unearned revenues fafs0002as</title>
      <link>/2017/04/25/inventory-ppe-unearned-revenues-fafs0002as/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 10:07:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/25/inventory-ppe-unearned-revenues-fafs0002as/</guid>
      <description>Remember: Discounts decrease the cost of purchased inventory and hence, decrease the cost of goods sold.
Capitalizing expenses means placing costs on the balance sheet and not in the income statement.
Recording unearned revenues means that revenues (in the income statement) will be recorded at a later point.
Impairment expenses decrease the profit.
Question: A company that wants to mislead investors by showing an inflated profit would use the following technique:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>impairment sales turnover roa fapi0006aan</title>
      <link>/2017/04/25/impairment-sales-turnover-roa-fapi0006aan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 10:01:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/25/impairment-sales-turnover-roa-fapi0006aan/</guid>
      <description>Remember: When recording an impairment the impairment expense account increases and the property, plant and equipment account decreases.
Question: Barrick Gold Corp., the world’s largest gold miner by production, took $8.7 billion of write-downs in the second quarter of 2016 and slashed its dividend, in a stark example of the fallout from gold’s precipitous price decline. With gold prices down by more than 20%, Barrick joined a host of other miners forced to write down the value of mines acquired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>revaluation ppe fapi0005au</title>
      <link>/2017/04/25/revaluation-ppe-fapi0005au/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 09:32:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/25/revaluation-ppe-fapi0005au/</guid>
      <description>Remember: Under the revaluation model an increase or decrease in the value of an asset is first recorded in an equity account (e.g., revaluation adjustment account) under the other comprehensive income section.
Question: Company Carrs revalued a piece of Property, plant and equipment (PPE) from $100,000 (cost: $150,000 less accumulated depreciation of $50,000) to $120,000 with the following entry: increase the Accumulated depreciation account $50,000, decrease the PPE account $30,000 and increase the Revaluation adjustment account $20,000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>low depreciation expense fapi0004au</title>
      <link>/2017/04/25/low-depreciation-expense-fapi0004au/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 09:24:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/25/low-depreciation-expense-fapi0004au/</guid>
      <description>Remember: Depreciation expense (straight-line method) = (Carrying amount - Residual value) / Remaining useful life
Question: If a company would want to show a low depreciation expenses in the first year after purchasing property, plant and equipment then it would:
Use a low residual value when calculating the depreciation expense under the straight-line method
Use a high residual value when calculating the depreciation expense under the straight-line method
Use a short useful life when calculating the depreciation expense under the straight-line method</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intangibles capitalization and expenses fapi0003es</title>
      <link>/2017/04/25/intangibles-capitalization-and-expenses-fapi0003es/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 08:57:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/25/intangibles-capitalization-and-expenses-fapi0003es/</guid>
      <description>Remember: Expenses are increased when the owner’s equity decreases (a) because cash decreases or rights to cash or services (e.g., prepayments, value assets) decrease or (b) because obligations to offer cash or services increase (e.g., unearned revenues).
AstraZeneca Plc is a British-Swedish multinational pharmaceutical company headquartered in London, United Kingdom. AstraZeneca prepares its consolidated financial statements in accordance with IFRS. AstraZeneca, alongside other pharmaceutical companies, is dependent on the success of its Research &amp;amp; Development (R&amp;amp;D) program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inventory cogs nrv fai0003as</title>
      <link>/2017/04/25/inventory-cogs-nrv-fai0003as/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 08:23:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/25/inventory-cogs-nrv-fai0003as/</guid>
      <description>Remember: The Net Realizable Value (NRV) of inventory is the value for which the inventory can be sold. If the inventory cannot be sold for an amount higher than its cost (i.e., the NRV is lower than the cost of inventory) then the inventory should be reported at the NRV amount instead of its cost.
To record the decrease in the value of the inventory to its NRV the following journal entry is made: increase the cost of goods sold and decrease the inventory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ppe cost model fapi0002br</title>
      <link>/2017/04/25/ppe-cost-model-fapi0002br/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 07:54:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/25/ppe-cost-model-fapi0002br/</guid>
      <description>Remember: The cost of any asset is the sum of all the costs incurred to bring the asset to its intended use.
Question: Company A paid $10,788 cash for equipment used in the business. At the time of purchase the equipment had a list price of $19,315. When the balance sheet was prepared, the market value of the equipment was $20,886. Which of the three amounts is the most relevant amount that should be used for measurement subsequent to initial recognition under the cost model?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intangibles goodwill fapi0001aapaapae</title>
      <link>/2017/04/24/intangibles-goodwill-fapi0001aapaapae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 20:53:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/24/intangibles-goodwill-fapi0001aapaapae/</guid>
      <description>Remember: Goodwill = Purchase Price - Fair value of identifiable net assets (of seller)
Goodwill is an intangible asset with indefinite life that can be impaired.
Anheuser-Busch InBev reached an agreement in 2016 to buy SABMiller for a purchase price of $108 billion, making for the biggest beer acquisition on record and one of the largest in corporate history. The fair value of the net identifiable assets of SABMiller before the acquisition was $93 billion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ending inventory fai0002aap</title>
      <link>/2017/04/24/ending-inventory-fai0002aap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 20:11:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/24/ending-inventory-fai0002aap/</guid>
      <description>Remember: Beginning inventory + Purchases - Cost of Goods Sold = Ending inventory
Beginning inventory of 2015 = Ending inventory of 2014
Question: The ending inventory for the year ended December 31, 2014, is understated. How will this erros affect the net income for 2014 and 2015?
2014 overstated; 2015 understated
2014 overstated; 2015 no effect
2014 overstated; 2015 no effect
2014 understated; 2015 overstated
Solution: Point 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>depreciation gain cash fafs0001es</title>
      <link>/2017/04/24/depreciation-gain-cash-fafs0001es/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 19:26:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/24/depreciation-gain-cash-fafs0001es/</guid>
      <description>Remember: Cash (proceeds) from sale of property, plant and equipment = Value of the asset (net of amortization or depreciation) +/- Gain/Loss on sale.
In the indirect method of building the cash flow statement, the non-cash expenses (e.g., depreciation expense) or gains are added to the net profit to find the cash from operating activities.
Cash flow from investing activities relates to the purchase and sale of property, plant and equipment and intangible assets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>net realizable value situations fai0001ae</title>
      <link>/2017/04/24/net-realizable-value-situations-fai0001ae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 19:02:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/24/net-realizable-value-situations-fai0001ae/</guid>
      <description>Remember: The Net Realizable Value (NRV) of inventory is the value for which the inventory can be sold. If the inventory cannot be sold for an amount higher than its cost (i.e., the NRV is lower than the cost of inventory) then the inventory should be reported at the NRV amount instead of its cost.
Question: Which of the points below describes a situation where the Net Realizable Value is higher than the cost of inventory?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a website with accounting exercises built with the blogdown package. The theme was forked from @jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme and modified by Yihui Xie. The content of this website is for educational purposes only and contains fictitious examples.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>